Guide to the Oscar I. Norwich Collection of Maps of Africa and Its Islands, 1486 - ca. 1865 NORWICH
David Rumsey Map Center
- Africa. -- Barcelona: Anonymous; Anonymous, Unknown; NOR 0142; : Colored; 34.5 cm. x 42 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Prime meridian through Madrid.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0142, p. 161
  Norwich number: 0142
  RID: MOA 0174
- Africa with the discoveries to May 1858 of Livingstone, Barth, Vogel and the Chadda expedition from documents in possession of the Royal Geographical Society. -- Edinburgh: A. Fullarton Co.; Swanston, G. H. (George H.) Exploration, 1860; NOR 0143; : Colored; 49 cm. x 38 cm.
  Source: Africa (1858)
  Descriptive Notes: Map based on exploration of Livingstone and Barth. Insets include Cape Verde Islands, Delta of the Niger, Cape Colony and Mauritius. Right hand side (top and bottom): 64; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0143, p. 162
  Norwich number: 0143
  RID: MOA 0213
- Africa. -- London: Tallis, John, 1815 or 6-1876; Tallis, John, 1815 or 6-1876; Tallis, John, 1815 or 6-1876; Marchant, J., 1880; NOR 0144; Steel: Outline color; 24 cm. x 32 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Five engraved vignettes are seen, an Arab family of Algeria, Bosjeman Hottentots, a view of St. Helena, a Bedouin Arabs' encampment and Korranna Hottentots. Illustrations drawn by J. Marchant and engraved by J.H. Kernot; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0144, p. 163
  Norwich number: 0144
  RID: MOA 0188
- Africa. -- Edinburgh: W. A.K. Johnston Limited; Johnston, Alexander Keith, 1804-1871; Johnston, Alexander Keith, 1804-1871, 1843; NOR 0145; : Outline color; 58.5 cm. x 49 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Bottom right: National Atlas 34; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0145, p. 164
  Norwich number: 0145
  RID: MOA 0268
- Map of Africa Showing its most Recent Discoveries. -- Philadelphia: Mitchell, S. Augustus (Samuel Augustus), 1792-1868; Mitchell, S. Augustus (Samuel Augustus), 1792-1868; Mitchell, S. Augustus (Samuel Augustus), 1792-1868, 1881; NOR 0146; : Colored; 27 cm. x 34 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "First appeared in Mitchell's New General Atlas in 1867". Map shows expedition routes of Stanley and Livingstone. Inset: Island of St. Helena ( place where Napoleon was buried). Top right: 120; Prime meridian through Washington.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0146, p. 165
  Norwich number: 0146
  RID: MOA 0175
- Africa. -- Weimer: Georgraphisches Institut; Graf, Adolph; Graf, Adolph; Graf, Adolph Exploration, No date; NOR 0147; : Colored; 53 cm. x 64 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Due to the discoveries on the map, it was probably published between 1867-1881. Top right: 55; Prime meridian through Ferro Island and Paris.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0147, p. 166
  Norwich number: 0147
  RID: MOA 0297
- Afrique Physique. = Physical map of Africa. -- Paris: Migeon, J.; Migeon, J.; Migeon, J., 1891; NOR 0148; : Colored; 31 cm. x 42 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Insets: Engraving of diamond fields by Fillatreau and Soudain. Heights of peaks and depths of lakes in Africa.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0148, p. 167
  Norwich number: 0148
  RID: MOA 0176
- Tabula Moderna Secunde Porcionis Aphriee. = Modern map of second half of Africa. -- Strasbourg: Schott, Johann, 1477-1548; Waldseemuller, Martin, 1470-1521?, 1513; NOR 0149; Woodcut: Colored; 35 cm. x 50 cm.
  Source: Waldseemuller's Ptolemy atlas (1513)
  Descriptive Notes: Companion map to NOR 0286. Waldseemuller compiled an atlas which included Ptolemy based maps. This map was reissued in "Strasbourg in 1520, 1522 and 1525; in Lyons in 1535, and Vienna in 1541".
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0149, p. 169
  Norwich number: 0149
  RID: MOA 0328
  Africa -- Southern Africa -- 16th c.
- Tabu. Nova Partis Aphri. = New map of part of Africa. -- Lyons: Trechsel, Melchior, fl. 1529-1549; Trechsel, Gaspard, fl. 1529-1549; Waldseemuller, Martin, 1470-1521?, 1535; NOR 0150; Woodcut: Uncolored; 30 cm. x 42 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Based on Waldseemuller's map (see NOR 0149). Border and ornament are by Hans Holbein and Graf. The reissued map includes three kings on their thrones, an elephant, a cockatrice and two serpents, while the King of Portugal rides a bridled sea monster.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0150, p. 170
  Norwich number: 0150
  RID: MOA 0124
- Africa Nuova Tavola. = New map of Africa. -- Venice: Valgrisi, Vincenzo, fl. 1540-1572; Ruscelli, Girolamo, d. ca. 1565., 1561-1662; NOR 0151; Copperplate: Uncolored; 18 cm. x 24 cm.
  Source: La Geograpfia di Claudio Tolomeo Alessandrino, Nouvamente tradatta di Greco in Italiano ... (1561)
  Descriptive Notes: Typical Italian engraved stippled seas and anthill mountain ranges. Later editions appeared in 1598 and 1599.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0151, p. 171
  Norwich number: 0151
  RID: MOA 0149
- Africae Pars meridionalior. = Southern Africa. -- Leiden: Guyot, Christoffle (printer); Bertius, Petrus, 1565-1629, 1606; NOR 0153; : Uncolored; 8.5 cm. x 12 cm.
  Source: Barent Langene's Caert Thressor (1606)
  Descriptive Notes: " ... issued originally in 1598, then at six different periods until 1618." Includes a sea monster in the Aethiopicus Oceanus. Highly detailed coastline. Bottom right: Cgs. Title across top: La Pointe d'Afrique. Top right: 105.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0153, p. 173
  Norwich number: 0153
  RID: MOA 0035
  Africa -- Southern Africa -- 17th c.
- Aethiopia Inferior vel Exterior. Partes magis Septentrionales, quae hic desiderantur, vide in tabula Aethiopiae Superioris. = Southern Africa ... -- Amsterdam: Blaeu, Willem Janszoon, 1571-1638; Blaeu, Willem Janszoon, 1571-1638, 1635; NOR 0154; : Outline color; 38 cm. x 50 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Title of cartouche is on an ox skin being held up by natives. Monkeys and tortoises surround the base. Various types of animals decorate the mainland, while the sea contain sailing ships.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0154, p. 174
  Norwich number: 0154
  RID: MOA 0096
- Polus Antarcticus. = Antarctic Circle. -- Amsterdam: Jansson, Jan, 1588-1664; Jansson, Jan, 1588-1664, 1637; NOR 0155; : Colored; 43 cm. x 49 cm.
  Source: Appendix Nova Atlanti (1647)
  Descriptive Notes: View of the Antarctic Circle includes Africa, South America and part of the Australian coastline.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0155, p. 176
  Norwich number: 0155
  RID: MOA 0209
  Oceans -- Antarctic circle -- 17th c.
- Chorographia originis Nili juxta observationem Odoardi Lopez. Fol. 55. Chorographia Originis Nili ... ex Arabum Geographia deprompta. Fol. 53. Vera et Genuina Fontium Nili Topographia facta a P. Petro Pais ... 1618. Fol. 56. = Three maps of the origins of the Nile according to Duarte Lopez, to Arab geography and Peter Pais. -- Amsterdam: Kircher, Athanasius, 1602-1680; Kircher, Athanasius, 1602-1680 Exploration, 1652; NOR 0156; : Uncolored; 46 cm. x 36 cm.
  Source: Oedipus Aegyptiacus (1652)
  Descriptive Notes: Includes three maps on one sheet. "Kircher is reputed to be the first to have described the finding of the Nile ... " Title across top: I Conismas II Tom. I Fol. 53. Upper right: Tomus I.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0156, p. 177
  Norwich number: 0156
  RID: MOA 0141
- Hydrophylacium Africae precipuum, in Montibus Lunae Situm, Lacus et Flumina praecipua fundens ubi et nova inventio Originis Nili describitur. = Map of southern Africa showing sources of the Nile in a cavern beneath the Mountains of the Moon. -- Amsterdam: Kircher, Athanasius, 1602-1680; Kircher, Athanasius, 1602-1680, 1665; NOR 0157; : Colored; 34 cm. x 41 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Illustrates Kircher's view on the source of the Nile. Oval-shaped cartouche is surrounded by cherubs and angels. Upper right: Tomus 1.72.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0157, p. 178
  Norwich number: 0157
  RID: MOA 0250
- Basse Aethiopie qui Comprend les Royaume de Congo, Coste, et Pays des Cafres, Empires du Monomotapa, et Monoemugi. = Southern Africa comprising the kingdom of Congo, coast of Kaffraria, empires of Monomotapa and Monoemugi. -- Paris: Mariette, Pierre, 1603-1657; Sanson, Nicolas, 1600-1667; Sanson, Nicolas, 1600-1667, 1655; NOR 0158; : Colored; 42 cm. x 56 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "The fictitious states are given fictious boundaries and the interior is marked with large cities .. "
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0158, p. 180
  Norwich number: 0158
  RID: MOA 0203
- Aethiopia Inferior vel Exterior. = Southern Africa. -- London: Ogilby, John, 1600-1676; Ogilby, John, 1600-1676, 1670; NOR 0159; : Outline color; 28 cm. x 36 cm.
  Source: Africa, being an Accurate Description of the Regions of Egypt, Barbary, Lybia and Billedulgerid ... (1670)
  Descriptive Notes: Similar to Bleau's map (see NOR 0154). Map also appeared in Dutch, French and German editions. Probably engraved by Jacob van Meurs.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0159, p. 181
  Norwich number: 0159
  RID: MOA 0251
- Monomotapa et la Cafrerie. = Monomotapa and Kaffraria. -- Paris: Thiery, Denys; Manesson-Mallet, Allain, 1630?-1706?, 1683; NOR 0160; Copperplate: Colored; 14 cm. x 10 cm.
  Source: Description de L'Univers
  Descriptive Notes: Reprinted in 1686 with German text. Across the top: De L'Afrique. Figure XLIV. 115.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0160, p. 182
  Norwich number: 0160
  RID: MOA 0329
- Lo creddero nato dalle della Luna i Geografi a si moderni Riportarono ghesi la gloriosa distinnotitia, che mi ferui per regolare l'Abissinia, guista le relationi accreditate del P. Baldassar Tellez, e del Ladolfo. = Born of the most recent geographical findings. -- Venice: Coronelli, Vincenzo, 1650-1718; Coronelli, Vincenzo, 1650-1718, 1688; NOR 0162; : Colored; 45 cm. x 25 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Gore of Africa from Coronelli's globe map (see map 0052).
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0162, p. 184
  Norwich number: 0162
  RID: MOA 0252
- Nieuwe Caarte van Kaap de Goede Hoop en't Zuyderdeel van Africa. = New map of Cape of Good Hope and southern part of Africa. -- Amsterdam: Ottens, R. (Reinier),1698-1750; Ottens, J. (Josua), 1704-1765; Ottens, R. (Reinier),1698-1750; Ottens, J. (Josua), 1704-1765, 1700; NOR 0163; : Colored; 44 cm. x 56 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Inset: De Hollandsche vesting aan het voorgebergte de Goede Hoop and Tafel-Bay aan het voorgebergte de Goede Hoop; Top right: Pag. 48.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0163, p. 185
  Norwich number: 0163
  RID: MOA 0253
  Africa -- Cape of Good Hope -- 17th c.
- Africae Pars Australis. = Southern Africa. -- Munich: Scherer, Heinrich, 1628-1704; Scherer, Heinrich, 1628-1704, 1702; NOR 0164; : Colored; 23 cm. x 35 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Identical style to Scherer's earlier map (see NOR 0062). Includes a cartouche with animals, flying fish, sailing vessel and a sea serpent.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0164, p. 187
  Norwich number: 0164
  RID: MOA 0170
  Africa -- Southern Africa -- 18th c.
- Carte du Royaume de Congo, du Monomotapa et de la Cafrerie, Dressee sur les Memoires les plus exacts et les observations les plus Nouvelles. = Map of the kingdom of the Congo, Monomotapa and Kaffraria based on recent observations. -- Amsterdam: Gueudeville, Nicolas, ca. 1654-ca. 1721; Chatelain, Henri Abraham, 1719; NOR 0165; : Colored; 39 cm. x 52 cm.
  Source: Atlas Historique et Methodique
  Descriptive Notes: Based on L'Isles maps. Includes note describing the Congo, Monomotapa and Kaffraria. Contains references to gold, in the form of 'Mines d'Or.' Top right: Tom. VI, No. 15, Pag: 59.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0165, p. 188
  Norwich number: 0165
  RID: MOA 0122
- Coutumes, Moeurs et Habillemens des Peuples qui Habitent aux Environs du Cap de Bonne Esperance avec une Description des Animaux et Reptiles qui se Trouvent dans ce Pais. = Dress and customs of the inhabitants of the Cape of Good Hope. -- Amsterdam: Gueudeville, Nicolas, ca. 1654-ca. 1721; Chatelain, Henri Abraham; Claudius, Heinrich, ca. 1655-ca. 1697, 1719; NOR 0166; : Colored; 36 cm. x 44 cm.
  Source: Atlas Historique
  Descriptive Notes: Includes ten engravings of natives and animals and Tachard's map (see NOR 0161). Title of map: Carte des Pays et des Peuples de Bonne Esperance. Nouvellement decouverts par les Hollands. Top right, Tom. VI. No. 18. Pag. 74.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0166, p. 189
  Norwich number: 0166
  RID: MOA 0228
  Africa -- Cape of Good Hope -- 18th c.
- Partie Meridionale D'Afrique ou se trouvent La Basse Guinee, La Cafrerie, Le Monomotapa, Le Monoemugi, Le Zanguebar et L'Isle de Madagascar. = Southern part of Africa ... -- Paris: Fer, Nicolas de, 1646-1720; Fer, Nicolas de, 1646-1720; Fer, Nicolas de, 1646-1720, 1715; NOR 0167; : Colored; 21 cm. x 31 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Legend states the discovery of the Cape of Good Hope by Bartholomew Diaz in 1486. Cartouche includes a galleon and a whale.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0167, p. 190
  Norwich number: 0167
  RID: MOA 0254
- La Basse Ethiopie en Afrique avec les Royaumes qui en dependent, ses Bayes et Rivieres, suivant les Memoires les plus recens des Voyageurs, nouvellement mise en lumiere par ... = Southern Ethiopia and dependent kingdoms ... -- Leiden: Aa, Pieter van der, 1659-1733; Aa, Pieter van der, 1659-1733, 1729; NOR 0169; : Colored; 28 cm. x 36 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Natives, river gods, sailing vessels, sailors and an elephant are illustrated on the cartouche.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0169, p. 192
  Norwich number: 0169
  RID: MOA 0255
- A new and accurate map of the southern parts of Africa Containing Lower Guinea, Monoemugi, Zanguebar, the Empire of Monomotapa, Country of the Cafres c. and the Island of Madagascar. Drawn from the best Authorities, assisted by the most approved Charts and Maps and adjusted by Astron. Observations. -- London: Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767; Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767, 1747; NOR 0170; : Colored; 35 cm. x 43 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Geographical features similar to L'Isle's map. Compass rose in the Indian Ocean; Prime meridian through London. Bottom left: No. 56.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0170, p. 193
  Norwich number: 0170
  RID: MOA 0104
- A new and accurate map of the southern parts of Africa Containing Lower Guinea, Monoemugi, Zanguebar, the Empire of Monomotapa, Country of the Cafres c. and the Island of Madagascar. Drawn from the best Authorities, assisted by the most approved Charts and Maps and adjusted by Astron. Observations. -- London: Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767; Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767, 1747; NOR 0170a; : Colored; 35 cm. x 43 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Duplicate map. Geographical features similar to L'Isle's map. Compass rose in the Indian Ocean; Prime meridian through London. Bottom left: No. 56.
  Norwich number: 0170a
  RID: MOA 0258
- Pays des Cafres. = Caffraria. -- Paris: Robert de Vaugondy, Didier, 1723-1786; Robert de Vaugondy, Didier, 1723-1786, 1749; NOR 0171; : Colored; 16 cm. x 23 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Includes mountain ranges and tribal kingdoms; Top right: 178.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0171, p. 194
  Norwich number: 0171
  RID: MOA 0183
- Congo Cafrerie par ... Corrige par Lamarche son successr. = Congo, Caffraria. -- Paris: Robert de Vaugondy, Gilles, 1688-1766; Robert de Vaugondy, Didier, 1723-1786; Robert de Vaugondy, Gilles, 1688-1766; Robert de Vaugondy, Didier, 1723-1786; Robert de Vaugondy, Gilles, 1688-1766; Robert de Vaugondy, Didier, 1723-1786, 1762-1795; NOR 0172; : Outline color; 24 cm. x 28 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: First issued in 1762. Includes inset of Cote d'Ajan.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0172, p. 195
  Norwich number: 0172
  RID: MOA 0169
- Carte du Canal de Mosambique, contenant L'Isle de Madagascar les Cotes d'Afrique, depuis le Cap de Bonne Esperance jusqu'a Melinde. = Map of the Mozambique Channel, Madagascar and the coast of Africa from the Cape of Good Hope to Melindi. -- Paris: Bonne, Rigobert, 1727-1794; Bonne, Rigobert, 1727-1794; Bonne, Rigobert, 1727-1794, 1762; NOR 0173; : Colored; 21 cm. x 32 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Inset of the Cape coast from St. Helena Bay to False Bay; Prime meridian through Ferro Island and Paris. Top left: Livre I, II, III, IV. Top right: No. 11.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0173, p. 196
  Norwich number: 0173
  RID: MOA 0100
  Africa -- Mozambique Channel -- 18th c.
- Partie de L'Afrique audela de L'Equateur, Comprenant Le Congo, La Cafreie c. = Africa south of the Equator comprising the Congo, Cafraria, etc. -- Paris: Desnos, L. C.; Brion de la Tour, Louis; Brion de la Tour, Louis, 1766; NOR 0175; : Colored; 22 cm. x 25 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Map surrounded by a decorative frame with information on the Congo, Monomotapa, Zanibar, Cape of Good Hope and the islands.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0175, p. 198
  Norwich number: 0175
  RID: MOA 0113
- Nieuwe en Naauwkerige Kaart van het Zuidlyk Gedeelte van Africa ... verbeeterd door W.A. Bachiene. = A new and accurate map of the southern parts of Africa, improved by W.A. Bachiene. -- Unknown: Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767; Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767; Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767, 1782; NOR 0176; : Uncolored; 34 cm. x 42 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: This is a Dutch version of the 1747 English edition of Bowen's map (see NOR 0170); Prime meridian through London.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0176, p. 199
  Norwich number: 0176
  RID: MOA 0108
- Africae Pars Meridionalis cum Promontorio Bonae Spei Accuratissime Delineato Opera ... = Southern part of Africa with Cape of Good Hope. -- Vienna: Lotter, Tobias Conrad, 1717-1777; Lotter, Tobias Conrad, 1717-1777, 1778; NOR 0177; : Colored; 46 cm. x 55 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Coastline provides inaccurate information. Hottentot tribes are illustrated throughout the mainland. Inset: Cape Fort, Saldanha Bay and the Cape of Good Hope. Dedicated to Domino Wilhelmo.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0177, p. 200
  Norwich number: 0177
  RID: MOA 0270
- Africa. -- Edinburgh Lizars, Daniel, 1760-1812, No date; NOR 0179; : Colored; 39 cm. x 86 cm.
  Source: The Edinburgh geographical and historial atlas (c. 1826-31)
  Descriptive Notes: First issued by Daniel Lizars Sr. in A New and Elegant General Atlas of the World ... (1808-12). Later the plates were reissued by Daniel Lizars Jr. (c. 1826-31). Across the top: Part of Africa. Top right: LVI; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0179, p. 202
  Norwich number: 0179
  RID: MOA 0318
- Carte de L'Afrique Meridionale ou Pays Entre la ligne le cap de Bonne Esperance et L'Isle de Madagascar. = Map of southern Africa or countries between the equator and the Cape of Good Hope and Madagascar. -- Amsterdam: Leth, Hendrick de, No date; NOR 0180; : Colored; 49 cm. x 57.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Originally issued by the Visscher family in 1710. Hendrik de Leth, married into the Visscher family took over the business and imprinted this map with his name. Also issued by Jan Barend Elwe (see NOR 0180a). Two insets are shown, Cape Peninsula and Plan and elevation of Table Bay.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0180, p. 203
  Norwich number: 0180
  RID: MOA 0246
- Carte de L'Afrique Meridionale ou Pays Entre la ligne le cap de Bonne Esperance et L'Isle de Madagascar. = Map of southern Africa or countries between the equator and the Cape of Good Hope and Madagascar. -- Amsterdam: Elwe, Jan Barend; Elwe, Jan Barend, 1792; NOR 0180a; : Colored; 49 cm. x 57.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Duplicate map. Originally issued by the Visscher family in 1710. Hendrik de Leth, married into the Visscher family took over the business and imprinted this map with his name. Two insets are shown, Cape Peninsula and Plan and elevation of Table Bay.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0180a, p. 203
  Norwich number: 0180a
  RID: MOA 0247
- Carta geografica de Africa del Capo de bon Esperanze sino al Regno et Imperio Monamotapo e Ria de la Goa. Scoperto dell' Citadino e Commandante ... = Map of Africa from Cape of Good Hope to the kingdom of Monomotapa ... -- Unknown: Pisani, Almoro Alvise, 1754-1808; Pisani, Almoro Alvise, 1754-1808, 1793; NOR 0183; manuscript map: Colored; 36 cm. x 61 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Across the bottom reads, Landtogt gedaan door de Zuid-Kust van Africa in den Jaare 1781 tot 1793 door Louis Almaro Pisani Burger Commandant en Ingezeetenen der Colonie Zwellendam; Inset of Port Natal.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0183, p. 207
  Norwich number: 0183
  RID: MOA 0205
- Afrique Meridionale. = Southern Africa. -- Paris: Lapie, M. (Pierre), 1779-1850; Lapie, M. (Pierre), 1779-1850; Lapie, M. (Pierre), 1779-1850, 1809; NOR 0184; : Outline color; 21.5 cm. x 29 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Pellicier (script engraver). Across top: Longitude du Meridien de Paris; Prime meridian through Paris.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0184, p. 209
  Norwich number: 0184
  RID: MOA 0325
  Africa -- Southern Africa -- 19th c.
- Southern Africa. -- London: Cadell and Davies, Strand, and Longman, Hurst, Rees and Orme; Pinkerton, John, 1758-1826; Pinkerton, John, 1758-1826; Herbert, L., 1809; NOR 0186; : Colored; 50 cm. x 69 cm.
  Source: (British edition)
  Descriptive Notes: An American edition was issued by Inskeep and Bradford in 1815 (see NOR 0186a).
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0186, p. 211
  Norwich number: 0186
  RID: MOA 0314
- Southern Africa. -- Philadelphia: Inskeep and Bradford; Pinkerton, John, 1758-1826; Pinkerton, John, 1758-1826; Herbert, L., 1815; NOR 0186a; : Colored; 50 cm. x 69 cm.
  Source: Pinkerton's Modern Atlas (1815) (American edition)
  Descriptive Notes: A British edition was issued by Cadell and Davies, Strand, and Longman, Hurst, Rees and Orme in 1809 (see NOR 0186). Title across top: Pinkerton's Modern Atlas.
  Norwich number: 0186a
  RID: MOA 0315
- Vicariati Apostolici nel Congo, Capo di Buona Speranza, Natal, e S. Ma. Mayotta, Nossibe Madagascar Prelazia di Mozambico. -- Unknown: Anonymous; Anonymous, No date; NOR 0187; : Colored; 47 cm. x 62 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: " ... probably originated from the Vatican in Rome. Shows southern Africa divided into its various states and colonies." Top left: TAV. CXII.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0187, p. 212
  Norwich number: 0187
  RID: MOA 0307
  Africa -- Southern Africa -- No date
- Afrique Meridionale. = Southern Africa. -- Paris: Brue, Adrien Hubert, 1786-1832; Brue, Adrien Hubert, 1786-1832, 1828; NOR 0188; : Colored; 36 cm. x 51 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Insets, enlargement of southern tip of Africa, islands northeast of Madagascar, Mascareignes islands, Kerguelen island. Prime meridian through London; Top right: 'Atlas, en 65 feuilles, No. 53'.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0188, p. 213
  Norwich number: 0188
  RID: MOA 0115